{
  "ALT_ALIZE_A_BR_37_C": {
    "@context": {
      "@vocab": "https://api.altered.gg/?_format=jsonld#",
      "hydra": "http://www.w3.org/ns/hydra/core#",
      "news": "CardHistoryData/news",
      "cardHistories": "CardHistoryData/cardHistories"
    },
    "@type": "CardHistoryData",
    "@id": "/.well-known/genid/3b6fece97690fb6b2c26",
    "news": {
      "@type": "CardHistory",
      "@id": "/.well-known/genid/0615751467b750eeb8ad",
      "id": "238",
      "fromDate": "2025-05-13T10:25:24+00:00",
      "type": "UNSUSPENDED",
      "name": "Unsuspension of Gericht, Revered Duelist",
      "description": "https://www.altered.gg/news/whispers-from-the-maze-season-patch",
      "answer": "As of this ruling, all Gericht are unsuspended. The effects of some of them has been updated.",
      "question": "Which versions of Gericht, Revered Duelist are legal and in which format?"
    },
    "cardHistories": [
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/0615751467b750eeb8ad",
        "id": "238",
        "fromDate": "2025-05-13T10:25:24+00:00",
        "type": "UNSUSPENDED",
        "name": "Unsuspension of Gericht, Revered Duelist",
        "description": "https://www.altered.gg/news/whispers-from-the-maze-season-patch",
        "answer": "As of this ruling, all Gericht are unsuspended. The effects of some of them has been updated.",
        "question": "Which versions of Gericht, Revered Duelist are legal and in which format?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/24f74790bd0f6e713973",
        "id": "239",
        "fromDate": "2025-04-04T10:25:24+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Instead means the replaced steps never happened",
        "answer": "No.",
        "question": "Can the Rare version of Gericht, Revered Duelist trigger an effect \"When a Character gains Fleeting —\"?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/70513182e6b4b2cae052",
        "id": "237",
        "fromDate": "2025-02-01T10:25:24+00:00",
        "type": "SUSPENDED",
        "name": "Suspension of Unique Gericht, Revered Duelist ",
        "description": "https://www.altered.gg/news/trial-by-frost-season-patch",
        "answer": "The Unique versions (Bravos or Lyra) of Gericht, Revered Duelist, were temporarily suspended in all versions of Constructed Format (1vs1, 2vs2 and Free for All). This suspension ended on the 13th of May, 2025",
        "question": "Which versions of Gericht, Revered Duelist are legal and in which format?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/55c5316f59f81189c4e8",
        "id": "236",
        "fromDate": "2025-01-31T10:25:24+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Gaining a status you already have",
        "answer": "It gains Fleeting again (which in general doesn't change anything, but gives him a boost). The power of the Common version of Gericht is an exception to the general rule that a Character cannot gain Fleeting if it's already Fleeting.",
        "question": "What happens if (Common) Gericht, Revered Duelist is already Fleeting and should gain Fleeting due to another effect?"
      }
    ]
  },
  "ALT_ALIZE_A_BR_37_R1": {
    "@context": {
      "@vocab": "https://api.altered.gg/?_format=jsonld#",
      "hydra": "http://www.w3.org/ns/hydra/core#",
      "news": "CardHistoryData/news",
      "cardHistories": "CardHistoryData/cardHistories"
    },
    "@type": "CardHistoryData",
    "@id": "/.well-known/genid/121f6788eb1c79584d9b",
    "news": {
      "@type": "CardHistory",
      "@id": "/.well-known/genid/9de7f9a6c2a021ac5b34",
      "id": "238",
      "fromDate": "2025-05-13T10:25:24+00:00",
      "type": "UNSUSPENDED",
      "name": "Unsuspension of Gericht, Revered Duelist",
      "description": "https://www.altered.gg/news/whispers-from-the-maze-season-patch",
      "answer": "As of this ruling, all Gericht are unsuspended. The effects of some of them has been updated.",
      "question": "Which versions of Gericht, Revered Duelist are legal and in which format?"
    },
    "cardHistories": [
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/9de7f9a6c2a021ac5b34",
        "id": "238",
        "fromDate": "2025-05-13T10:25:24+00:00",
        "type": "UNSUSPENDED",
        "name": "Unsuspension of Gericht, Revered Duelist",
        "description": "https://www.altered.gg/news/whispers-from-the-maze-season-patch",
        "answer": "As of this ruling, all Gericht are unsuspended. The effects of some of them has been updated.",
        "question": "Which versions of Gericht, Revered Duelist are legal and in which format?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/554a7371b05f35c0ea09",
        "id": "239",
        "fromDate": "2025-04-04T10:25:24+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Instead means the replaced steps never happened",
        "answer": "No.",
        "question": "Can the Rare version of Gericht, Revered Duelist trigger an effect \"When a Character gains Fleeting —\"?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/14570c5e70ad58278c58",
        "id": "237",
        "fromDate": "2025-02-01T10:25:24+00:00",
        "type": "SUSPENDED",
        "name": "Suspension of Unique Gericht, Revered Duelist ",
        "description": "https://www.altered.gg/news/trial-by-frost-season-patch",
        "answer": "The Unique versions (Bravos or Lyra) of Gericht, Revered Duelist, were temporarily suspended in all versions of Constructed Format (1vs1, 2vs2 and Free for All). This suspension ended on the 13th of May, 2025",
        "question": "Which versions of Gericht, Revered Duelist are legal and in which format?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/ea0744abb0ca1aeab75b",
        "id": "236",
        "fromDate": "2025-01-31T10:25:24+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Gaining a status you already have",
        "answer": "It gains Fleeting again (which in general doesn't change anything, but gives him a boost). The power of the Common version of Gericht is an exception to the general rule that a Character cannot gain Fleeting if it's already Fleeting.",
        "question": "What happens if (Common) Gericht, Revered Duelist is already Fleeting and should gain Fleeting due to another effect?"
      }
    ]
  },
  "ALT_ALIZE_B_BR_37_C": {
    "@context": {
      "@vocab": "https://api.altered.gg/?_format=jsonld#",
      "hydra": "http://www.w3.org/ns/hydra/core#",
      "news": "CardHistoryData/news",
      "cardHistories": "CardHistoryData/cardHistories"
    },
    "@type": "CardHistoryData",
    "@id": "/.well-known/genid/ea4f213701e189d9303a",
    "news": {
      "@type": "CardHistory",
      "@id": "/.well-known/genid/8f5cc0dcf4f843699ca8",
      "id": "238",
      "fromDate": "2025-05-13T10:25:24+00:00",
      "type": "UNSUSPENDED",
      "name": "Unsuspension of Gericht, Revered Duelist",
      "description": "https://www.altered.gg/news/whispers-from-the-maze-season-patch",
      "answer": "As of this ruling, all Gericht are unsuspended. The effects of some of them has been updated.",
      "question": "Which versions of Gericht, Revered Duelist are legal and in which format?"
    },
    "cardHistories": [
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/8f5cc0dcf4f843699ca8",
        "id": "238",
        "fromDate": "2025-05-13T10:25:24+00:00",
        "type": "UNSUSPENDED",
        "name": "Unsuspension of Gericht, Revered Duelist",
        "description": "https://www.altered.gg/news/whispers-from-the-maze-season-patch",
        "answer": "As of this ruling, all Gericht are unsuspended. The effects of some of them has been updated.",
        "question": "Which versions of Gericht, Revered Duelist are legal and in which format?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/5c2d79cc8734533a4cdc",
        "id": "239",
        "fromDate": "2025-04-04T10:25:24+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Instead means the replaced steps never happened",
        "answer": "No.",
        "question": "Can the Rare version of Gericht, Revered Duelist trigger an effect \"When a Character gains Fleeting —\"?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/7d0a11ea2f8dd00d8917",
        "id": "237",
        "fromDate": "2025-02-01T10:25:24+00:00",
        "type": "SUSPENDED",
        "name": "Suspension of Unique Gericht, Revered Duelist ",
        "description": "https://www.altered.gg/news/trial-by-frost-season-patch",
        "answer": "The Unique versions (Bravos or Lyra) of Gericht, Revered Duelist, were temporarily suspended in all versions of Constructed Format (1vs1, 2vs2 and Free for All). This suspension ended on the 13th of May, 2025",
        "question": "Which versions of Gericht, Revered Duelist are legal and in which format?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/20dc97ed641f11a7532e",
        "id": "236",
        "fromDate": "2025-01-31T10:25:24+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Gaining a status you already have",
        "answer": "It gains Fleeting again (which in general doesn't change anything, but gives him a boost). The power of the Common version of Gericht is an exception to the general rule that a Character cannot gain Fleeting if it's already Fleeting.",
        "question": "What happens if (Common) Gericht, Revered Duelist is already Fleeting and should gain Fleeting due to another effect?"
      }
    ]
  },
  "ALT_ALIZE_B_BR_37_R1": {
    "@context": {
      "@vocab": "https://api.altered.gg/?_format=jsonld#",
      "hydra": "http://www.w3.org/ns/hydra/core#",
      "news": "CardHistoryData/news",
      "cardHistories": "CardHistoryData/cardHistories"
    },
    "@type": "CardHistoryData",
    "@id": "/.well-known/genid/65b1849fc07c1e2587e1",
    "news": {
      "@type": "CardHistory",
      "@id": "/.well-known/genid/2e599bf82a82aee0a97e",
      "id": "238",
      "fromDate": "2025-05-13T10:25:24+00:00",
      "type": "UNSUSPENDED",
      "name": "Unsuspension of Gericht, Revered Duelist",
      "description": "https://www.altered.gg/news/whispers-from-the-maze-season-patch",
      "answer": "As of this ruling, all Gericht are unsuspended. The effects of some of them has been updated.",
      "question": "Which versions of Gericht, Revered Duelist are legal and in which format?"
    },
    "cardHistories": [
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/2e599bf82a82aee0a97e",
        "id": "238",
        "fromDate": "2025-05-13T10:25:24+00:00",
        "type": "UNSUSPENDED",
        "name": "Unsuspension of Gericht, Revered Duelist",
        "description": "https://www.altered.gg/news/whispers-from-the-maze-season-patch",
        "answer": "As of this ruling, all Gericht are unsuspended. The effects of some of them has been updated.",
        "question": "Which versions of Gericht, Revered Duelist are legal and in which format?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/7cf2da719df740a98a3d",
        "id": "239",
        "fromDate": "2025-04-04T10:25:24+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Instead means the replaced steps never happened",
        "answer": "No.",
        "question": "Can the Rare version of Gericht, Revered Duelist trigger an effect \"When a Character gains Fleeting —\"?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/74e54f83d97c8e606e89",
        "id": "237",
        "fromDate": "2025-02-01T10:25:24+00:00",
        "type": "SUSPENDED",
        "name": "Suspension of Unique Gericht, Revered Duelist ",
        "description": "https://www.altered.gg/news/trial-by-frost-season-patch",
        "answer": "The Unique versions (Bravos or Lyra) of Gericht, Revered Duelist, were temporarily suspended in all versions of Constructed Format (1vs1, 2vs2 and Free for All). This suspension ended on the 13th of May, 2025",
        "question": "Which versions of Gericht, Revered Duelist are legal and in which format?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/3d2a7504b25cf8435080",
        "id": "236",
        "fromDate": "2025-01-31T10:25:24+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Gaining a status you already have",
        "answer": "It gains Fleeting again (which in general doesn't change anything, but gives him a boost). The power of the Common version of Gericht is an exception to the general rule that a Character cannot gain Fleeting if it's already Fleeting.",
        "question": "What happens if (Common) Gericht, Revered Duelist is already Fleeting and should gain Fleeting due to another effect?"
      }
    ]
  },
  "ALT_ALIZE_A_BR_37_R2": {
    "@context": {
      "@vocab": "https://api.altered.gg/?_format=jsonld#",
      "hydra": "http://www.w3.org/ns/hydra/core#",
      "news": "CardHistoryData/news",
      "cardHistories": "CardHistoryData/cardHistories"
    },
    "@type": "CardHistoryData",
    "@id": "/.well-known/genid/791dfbdaa0dc95d841d8",
    "news": {
      "@type": "CardHistory",
      "@id": "/.well-known/genid/a6c7fe0880d478e858bf",
      "id": "238",
      "fromDate": "2025-05-13T10:25:24+00:00",
      "type": "UNSUSPENDED",
      "name": "Unsuspension of Gericht, Revered Duelist",
      "description": "https://www.altered.gg/news/whispers-from-the-maze-season-patch",
      "answer": "As of this ruling, all Gericht are unsuspended. The effects of some of them has been updated.",
      "question": "Which versions of Gericht, Revered Duelist are legal and in which format?"
    },
    "cardHistories": [
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/a6c7fe0880d478e858bf",
        "id": "238",
        "fromDate": "2025-05-13T10:25:24+00:00",
        "type": "UNSUSPENDED",
        "name": "Unsuspension of Gericht, Revered Duelist",
        "description": "https://www.altered.gg/news/whispers-from-the-maze-season-patch",
        "answer": "As of this ruling, all Gericht are unsuspended. The effects of some of them has been updated.",
        "question": "Which versions of Gericht, Revered Duelist are legal and in which format?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/9ff05f140404f5c0bb79",
        "id": "239",
        "fromDate": "2025-04-04T10:25:24+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Instead means the replaced steps never happened",
        "answer": "No.",
        "question": "Can the Rare version of Gericht, Revered Duelist trigger an effect \"When a Character gains Fleeting —\"?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/0e5a8c4a5fff57b1662e",
        "id": "237",
        "fromDate": "2025-02-01T10:25:24+00:00",
        "type": "SUSPENDED",
        "name": "Suspension of Unique Gericht, Revered Duelist ",
        "description": "https://www.altered.gg/news/trial-by-frost-season-patch",
        "answer": "The Unique versions (Bravos or Lyra) of Gericht, Revered Duelist, were temporarily suspended in all versions of Constructed Format (1vs1, 2vs2 and Free for All). This suspension ended on the 13th of May, 2025",
        "question": "Which versions of Gericht, Revered Duelist are legal and in which format?"
      }
    ]
  },
  "ALT_ALIZE_A_LY_45_C": {
    "@context": {
      "@vocab": "https://api.altered.gg/?_format=jsonld#",
      "hydra": "http://www.w3.org/ns/hydra/core#",
      "news": "CardHistoryData/news",
      "cardHistories": "CardHistoryData/cardHistories"
    },
    "@type": "CardHistoryData",
    "@id": "/.well-known/genid/4ec61ef725d2fdb5bd60",
    "news": {
      "@type": "CardHistory",
      "@id": "/.well-known/genid/b529b35972e4d09fbba4",
      "id": "283",
      "fromDate": "2025-02-07T10:25:25+00:00",
      "type": "FUNCTIONAL_ERRATUM",
      "name": "Erratum of Icebound Tundra",
      "answer": "No.  Icebound Tundra will be updated in future printings to clarify it, previous wordings said:  When you play a Character in a region type where its base statistic is 0 — I gain a Trial counter.  Future printings will read:  When you play a Character — If it's in a terrain where its base statistic is 0, I gain 1 Trial counter. (The condition being after the — indicates that you check it at resolution).",
      "question": "If I play a Character with an ability that removes the Mountain terrain and a base stat of 0 in Mountain in a Mountain region , such as the Kraken or the Rare version of Persephone, does my Icebound Tundra gain a Trial counter?"
    },
    "cardHistories": [
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/5720e2dd15a901661ec8",
        "id": "285",
        "fromDate": "2025-03-09T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Choose not to sacrifice",
        "answer": "No. \"If you do\" doesn't mean you can choose, it means that if another effect prevents you from sacrificing the Icebound Landmark, you cannot create the Dragon Shade.",
        "question": "Can I choose not to sacrifice my Icebound Landmark when it gains a 3rd Trial counter?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/97ea9e0d4dafe758cfd1",
        "id": "282",
        "fromDate": "2025-02-07T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Multiple zero",
        "answer": "Icebound Tundra only gains 1 counter per Character played.",
        "question": "If I play a Character in a region where two or more of its base statistics are zero (such as an Ouroubouros Trickster), how many counters does my Icebound Tundra gain ?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/b529b35972e4d09fbba4",
        "id": "283",
        "fromDate": "2025-02-07T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "FUNCTIONAL_ERRATUM",
        "name": "Erratum of Icebound Tundra",
        "answer": "No.  Icebound Tundra will be updated in future printings to clarify it, previous wordings said:  When you play a Character in a region type where its base statistic is 0 — I gain a Trial counter.  Future printings will read:  When you play a Character — If it's in a terrain where its base statistic is 0, I gain 1 Trial counter. (The condition being after the — indicates that you check it at resolution).",
        "question": "If I play a Character with an ability that removes the Mountain terrain and a base stat of 0 in Mountain in a Mountain region , such as the Kraken or the Rare version of Persephone, does my Icebound Tundra gain a Trial counter?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/8ea14c79b5b696172406",
        "id": "284",
        "fromDate": "2025-01-31T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Sacrifice another way",
        "answer": "No. You only create the Dragon Shade when you successfully sacrifice the Icebound Landmark via its effect.",
        "question": "If I sacrifice an Icebound Landmark via another effect, such as (the Rare, Axiom version of) Boom!, can I create a Dragon Shade?"
      }
    ]
  },
  "ALT_ALIZE_A_LY_45_R1": {
    "@context": {
      "@vocab": "https://api.altered.gg/?_format=jsonld#",
      "hydra": "http://www.w3.org/ns/hydra/core#",
      "news": "CardHistoryData/news",
      "cardHistories": "CardHistoryData/cardHistories"
    },
    "@type": "CardHistoryData",
    "@id": "/.well-known/genid/7c6bea3f67cde7b08769",
    "news": {
      "@type": "CardHistory",
      "@id": "/.well-known/genid/9648dcbea67de5b42866",
      "id": "283",
      "fromDate": "2025-02-07T10:25:25+00:00",
      "type": "FUNCTIONAL_ERRATUM",
      "name": "Erratum of Icebound Tundra",
      "answer": "No.  Icebound Tundra will be updated in future printings to clarify it, previous wordings said:  When you play a Character in a region type where its base statistic is 0 — I gain a Trial counter.  Future printings will read:  When you play a Character — If it's in a terrain where its base statistic is 0, I gain 1 Trial counter. (The condition being after the — indicates that you check it at resolution).",
      "question": "If I play a Character with an ability that removes the Mountain terrain and a base stat of 0 in Mountain in a Mountain region , such as the Kraken or the Rare version of Persephone, does my Icebound Tundra gain a Trial counter?"
    },
    "cardHistories": [
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/082f1a641be18f820399",
        "id": "285",
        "fromDate": "2025-03-09T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Choose not to sacrifice",
        "answer": "No. \"If you do\" doesn't mean you can choose, it means that if another effect prevents you from sacrificing the Icebound Landmark, you cannot create the Dragon Shade.",
        "question": "Can I choose not to sacrifice my Icebound Landmark when it gains a 3rd Trial counter?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/cad17133192c9cb8bb19",
        "id": "282",
        "fromDate": "2025-02-07T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Multiple zero",
        "answer": "Icebound Tundra only gains 1 counter per Character played.",
        "question": "If I play a Character in a region where two or more of its base statistics are zero (such as an Ouroubouros Trickster), how many counters does my Icebound Tundra gain ?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/9648dcbea67de5b42866",
        "id": "283",
        "fromDate": "2025-02-07T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "FUNCTIONAL_ERRATUM",
        "name": "Erratum of Icebound Tundra",
        "answer": "No.  Icebound Tundra will be updated in future printings to clarify it, previous wordings said:  When you play a Character in a region type where its base statistic is 0 — I gain a Trial counter.  Future printings will read:  When you play a Character — If it's in a terrain where its base statistic is 0, I gain 1 Trial counter. (The condition being after the — indicates that you check it at resolution).",
        "question": "If I play a Character with an ability that removes the Mountain terrain and a base stat of 0 in Mountain in a Mountain region , such as the Kraken or the Rare version of Persephone, does my Icebound Tundra gain a Trial counter?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/82b93be3fe5ca1d6dcf6",
        "id": "284",
        "fromDate": "2025-01-31T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Sacrifice another way",
        "answer": "No. You only create the Dragon Shade when you successfully sacrifice the Icebound Landmark via its effect.",
        "question": "If I sacrifice an Icebound Landmark via another effect, such as (the Rare, Axiom version of) Boom!, can I create a Dragon Shade?"
      }
    ]
  },
  "ALT_ALIZE_A_MU_45_R2": {
    "@context": {
      "@vocab": "https://api.altered.gg/?_format=jsonld#",
      "hydra": "http://www.w3.org/ns/hydra/core#",
      "news": "CardHistoryData/news",
      "cardHistories": "CardHistoryData/cardHistories"
    },
    "@type": "CardHistoryData",
    "@id": "/.well-known/genid/d05617f6059568179be9",
    "news": {
      "@type": "CardHistory",
      "@id": "/.well-known/genid/f802274249b15fc336d6",
      "id": "311",
      "fromDate": "2025-02-05T10:25:25+00:00",
      "type": "FUNCTIONAL_ERRATUM",
      "name": "Erratum of Icebound Taiga",
      "answer": "Yes. The wording of Icebound Taiga has been updated to clarify it, previous wordings read:  \"When you play a Character in {V} — I gain a Trial counter.\"  Future printings will read:  \"When you play a Character — If it's in {V}, I gain 1 Trial counter.\" (The condition being after the — indicates that you check it at resolution).",
      "question": "If my Expedition is in a non-{V} region but I play a Character in it that turns it into {V}, such as Persephone, does my Icebound Taiga gain a Trial counter?"
    },
    "cardHistories": [
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/4a32832651337d1ec2f1",
        "id": "312",
        "fromDate": "2025-03-09T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Choose not to sacrifice",
        "answer": "No. \"If you do\" doesn't mean you can choose, it means that if another effect prevents you from sacrificing the Icebound Landmark, you cannot create the Dragon Shade.",
        "question": "Can I choose not to sacrifice my Icebound Landmark when it gains a 3rd Trial counter?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/f802274249b15fc336d6",
        "id": "311",
        "fromDate": "2025-02-05T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "FUNCTIONAL_ERRATUM",
        "name": "Erratum of Icebound Taiga",
        "answer": "Yes. The wording of Icebound Taiga has been updated to clarify it, previous wordings read:  \"When you play a Character in {V} — I gain a Trial counter.\"  Future printings will read:  \"When you play a Character — If it's in {V}, I gain 1 Trial counter.\" (The condition being after the — indicates that you check it at resolution).",
        "question": "If my Expedition is in a non-{V} region but I play a Character in it that turns it into {V}, such as Persephone, does my Icebound Taiga gain a Trial counter?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/888e4d79744c1f0c551f",
        "id": "310",
        "fromDate": "2025-01-31T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Sacrifice another way",
        "answer": "No. You only create the Dragon Shade when you successfully sacrifice the Icebound Landmark via its effect.",
        "question": "If I sacrifice an Icebound Landmark via another effect, such as (the Rare, Axiom version of) Boom!, can I create a Dragon Shade?"
      }
    ]
  },
  "ALT_ALIZE_B_BR_37_R2": {
    "@context": {
      "@vocab": "https://api.altered.gg/?_format=jsonld#",
      "hydra": "http://www.w3.org/ns/hydra/core#",
      "news": "CardHistoryData/news",
      "cardHistories": "CardHistoryData/cardHistories"
    },
    "@type": "CardHistoryData",
    "@id": "/.well-known/genid/2821729351b427695795",
    "news": {
      "@type": "CardHistory",
      "@id": "/.well-known/genid/9f6042f121b41d4609c1",
      "id": "238",
      "fromDate": "2025-05-13T10:25:24+00:00",
      "type": "UNSUSPENDED",
      "name": "Unsuspension of Gericht, Revered Duelist",
      "description": "https://www.altered.gg/news/whispers-from-the-maze-season-patch",
      "answer": "As of this ruling, all Gericht are unsuspended. The effects of some of them has been updated.",
      "question": "Which versions of Gericht, Revered Duelist are legal and in which format?"
    },
    "cardHistories": [
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/9f6042f121b41d4609c1",
        "id": "238",
        "fromDate": "2025-05-13T10:25:24+00:00",
        "type": "UNSUSPENDED",
        "name": "Unsuspension of Gericht, Revered Duelist",
        "description": "https://www.altered.gg/news/whispers-from-the-maze-season-patch",
        "answer": "As of this ruling, all Gericht are unsuspended. The effects of some of them has been updated.",
        "question": "Which versions of Gericht, Revered Duelist are legal and in which format?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/38a0ac6269a6123c76cb",
        "id": "239",
        "fromDate": "2025-04-04T10:25:24+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Instead means the replaced steps never happened",
        "answer": "No.",
        "question": "Can the Rare version of Gericht, Revered Duelist trigger an effect \"When a Character gains Fleeting —\"?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/9e5d8168767ce30012bb",
        "id": "237",
        "fromDate": "2025-02-01T10:25:24+00:00",
        "type": "SUSPENDED",
        "name": "Suspension of Unique Gericht, Revered Duelist ",
        "description": "https://www.altered.gg/news/trial-by-frost-season-patch",
        "answer": "The Unique versions (Bravos or Lyra) of Gericht, Revered Duelist, were temporarily suspended in all versions of Constructed Format (1vs1, 2vs2 and Free for All). This suspension ended on the 13th of May, 2025",
        "question": "Which versions of Gericht, Revered Duelist are legal and in which format?"
      }
    ]
  },
  "ALT_ALIZE_B_LY_35_C": {
    "@context": {
      "@vocab": "https://api.altered.gg/?_format=jsonld#",
      "hydra": "http://www.w3.org/ns/hydra/core#",
      "news": "CardHistoryData/news",
      "cardHistories": "CardHistoryData/cardHistories"
    },
    "@type": "CardHistoryData",
    "@id": "/.well-known/genid/da2a5ef21d49f5c2339e",
    "news": {
      "@type": "CardHistory",
      "@id": "/.well-known/genid/eb1d4b4f7eb2042b1828",
      "id": "274",
      "fromDate": "2025-10-03T10:25:24+00:00",
      "type": "BALANCING_ERRATUM",
      "name": "Erratum of Will-o'-the-Wisp (Common & Rare)",
      "description": "https://www.altered.gg/en-us/news/skybound-odyssey-season-patch",
      "answer": "Yes. The first printing of Will-o'-the-Wisp (Lyra Version) said \"If the Expedition facing me is in {O}, it can only move forward due to {O}.\"  Future versions will say:  \"If an Expedition facing me is in {O}, it can't move forward DURING DUSK except due to {O}.\"  This change doesn't affect the Unique versions of Will-O-the-Wisp, which still prevent moving forward outside of Dusk.",
      "question": "Did the text of this card change?"
    },
    "cardHistories": [
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/aa0851c338e0eac41002",
        "id": "276",
        "fromDate": "2025-10-03T10:25:24+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Move forward due to a Spell or another effect",
        "answer": "Yes. Note that as of October 2025, this is not true of the Common and Rare versions of Will'-O-the-Wisp, which only apply during Dusk.",
        "question": "If the Expedition facing it is in the proper terrain, does Will-O'-the-Wisp Unique prevent if from moving forward due to Small Step Giant Leap, Western Wind or similar abilities?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/eb1d4b4f7eb2042b1828",
        "id": "274",
        "fromDate": "2025-10-03T10:25:24+00:00",
        "type": "BALANCING_ERRATUM",
        "name": "Erratum of Will-o'-the-Wisp (Common & Rare)",
        "description": "https://www.altered.gg/en-us/news/skybound-odyssey-season-patch",
        "answer": "Yes. The first printing of Will-o'-the-Wisp (Lyra Version) said \"If the Expedition facing me is in {O}, it can only move forward due to {O}.\"  Future versions will say:  \"If an Expedition facing me is in {O}, it can't move forward DURING DUSK except due to {O}.\"  This change doesn't affect the Unique versions of Will-O-the-Wisp, which still prevent moving forward outside of Dusk.",
        "question": "Did the text of this card change?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/0a152e02c105519cacea",
        "id": "269",
        "fromDate": "2025-10-03T10:25:24+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Moving forward a different way",
        "description": "https://www.altered.gg/en-us/news/skybound-odyssey-season-patch",
        "answer": "As of October 2025, the Common and Rare versions of Will-o'-the-Wisp only apply during Dusk. It does prevent an Expedition from moving forward due to anything else during that phase, but not during the rest of the Day (which is when such effects would typically happen).  The Unique versions of  Will-o'-the-Wisp still apply as long as they are in play.",
        "question": "If the Expedition facing Will-o'-the-Wisp is in {O}, can it still move forward due to effects such as Small Step, Giant Leap?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/009dd5de8bda655418e3",
        "id": "266",
        "fromDate": "2025-02-19T10:25:24+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Blocking Magic Sleigh",
        "answer": "The Expedition moves forward two regions in one single step, Will-o-the-wisp cannot block it in the middle. (Of course it can prevent it from moving altogether if the starting region is the proper terrain.)",
        "question": "If the Expedition facing Will-o-the-Wisp moves forward, and contains a card such as The Magic Sleigh, allowing it to move two regions instead of one, what happens? Can it be blocked if the first move brings it in {O}?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/4a54619da97aa81318e3",
        "id": "271",
        "fromDate": "2025-02-03T10:25:24+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Gigantic Will'o'-the-wisp",
        "answer": "For a Gigantic Character, \"the Expedition facing me\" means \"the Expeditions facing me\". In the specific case of Gigantic Will-o-the-Wisp (Common or Rare, Lyra version), their effect means \"If any Expedition facing me is in {O}, that Expedition cannot move forward except due to {O}.\" (They don't need to both be in {O}).",
        "question": "If Will-o'-the-Wisp or a similar card becomes Gigantic (for example due to Eat Me Energy Bars), how does it affect the Expeditions facing it?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/738de80e68e53c265f08",
        "id": "270",
        "fromDate": "2025-02-03T10:25:24+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Multiple blocking",
        "answer": "That Expedition cannot move forward.",
        "question": "If two different effects state that an Expedition  1. can only move forward due to {V} and  2. can only move forward due to {O}, what happens?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/ffe9cb855e0d0bbecd26",
        "id": "273",
        "fromDate": "2024-08-28T10:25:24+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "No moving in the arena",
        "answer": "In the Arena, Expeditions can't move forward nor backwards since there's only one region. Any such effect becomes irrelevant.",
        "question": "What's the effect of Will-o'-the-Wisp in the arena, during a tie-breaker Day?"
      }
    ]
  },
  "ALT_ALIZE_B_LY_35_R1": {
    "@context": {
      "@vocab": "https://api.altered.gg/?_format=jsonld#",
      "hydra": "http://www.w3.org/ns/hydra/core#",
      "news": "CardHistoryData/news",
      "cardHistories": "CardHistoryData/cardHistories"
    },
    "@type": "CardHistoryData",
    "@id": "/.well-known/genid/99342b732f56b1600bf1",
    "news": {
      "@type": "CardHistory",
      "@id": "/.well-known/genid/05a62ecf60c192043b80",
      "id": "274",
      "fromDate": "2025-10-03T10:25:24+00:00",
      "type": "BALANCING_ERRATUM",
      "name": "Erratum of Will-o'-the-Wisp (Common & Rare)",
      "description": "https://www.altered.gg/en-us/news/skybound-odyssey-season-patch",
      "answer": "Yes. The first printing of Will-o'-the-Wisp (Lyra Version) said \"If the Expedition facing me is in {O}, it can only move forward due to {O}.\"  Future versions will say:  \"If an Expedition facing me is in {O}, it can't move forward DURING DUSK except due to {O}.\"  This change doesn't affect the Unique versions of Will-O-the-Wisp, which still prevent moving forward outside of Dusk.",
      "question": "Did the text of this card change?"
    },
    "cardHistories": [
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/2d59a0c5c8d8211555eb",
        "id": "276",
        "fromDate": "2025-10-03T10:25:24+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Move forward due to a Spell or another effect",
        "answer": "Yes. Note that as of October 2025, this is not true of the Common and Rare versions of Will'-O-the-Wisp, which only apply during Dusk.",
        "question": "If the Expedition facing it is in the proper terrain, does Will-O'-the-Wisp Unique prevent if from moving forward due to Small Step Giant Leap, Western Wind or similar abilities?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/05a62ecf60c192043b80",
        "id": "274",
        "fromDate": "2025-10-03T10:25:24+00:00",
        "type": "BALANCING_ERRATUM",
        "name": "Erratum of Will-o'-the-Wisp (Common & Rare)",
        "description": "https://www.altered.gg/en-us/news/skybound-odyssey-season-patch",
        "answer": "Yes. The first printing of Will-o'-the-Wisp (Lyra Version) said \"If the Expedition facing me is in {O}, it can only move forward due to {O}.\"  Future versions will say:  \"If an Expedition facing me is in {O}, it can't move forward DURING DUSK except due to {O}.\"  This change doesn't affect the Unique versions of Will-O-the-Wisp, which still prevent moving forward outside of Dusk.",
        "question": "Did the text of this card change?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/479727cce2bb9171b278",
        "id": "269",
        "fromDate": "2025-10-03T10:25:24+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Moving forward a different way",
        "description": "https://www.altered.gg/en-us/news/skybound-odyssey-season-patch",
        "answer": "As of October 2025, the Common and Rare versions of Will-o'-the-Wisp only apply during Dusk. It does prevent an Expedition from moving forward due to anything else during that phase, but not during the rest of the Day (which is when such effects would typically happen).  The Unique versions of  Will-o'-the-Wisp still apply as long as they are in play.",
        "question": "If the Expedition facing Will-o'-the-Wisp is in {O}, can it still move forward due to effects such as Small Step, Giant Leap?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/5097cfda4157e28d6e0b",
        "id": "266",
        "fromDate": "2025-02-19T10:25:24+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Blocking Magic Sleigh",
        "answer": "The Expedition moves forward two regions in one single step, Will-o-the-wisp cannot block it in the middle. (Of course it can prevent it from moving altogether if the starting region is the proper terrain.)",
        "question": "If the Expedition facing Will-o-the-Wisp moves forward, and contains a card such as The Magic Sleigh, allowing it to move two regions instead of one, what happens? Can it be blocked if the first move brings it in {O}?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/faa803a282110d32f3e5",
        "id": "271",
        "fromDate": "2025-02-03T10:25:24+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Gigantic Will'o'-the-wisp",
        "answer": "For a Gigantic Character, \"the Expedition facing me\" means \"the Expeditions facing me\". In the specific case of Gigantic Will-o-the-Wisp (Common or Rare, Lyra version), their effect means \"If any Expedition facing me is in {O}, that Expedition cannot move forward except due to {O}.\" (They don't need to both be in {O}).",
        "question": "If Will-o'-the-Wisp or a similar card becomes Gigantic (for example due to Eat Me Energy Bars), how does it affect the Expeditions facing it?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/342a84b0f232246cca2b",
        "id": "270",
        "fromDate": "2025-02-03T10:25:24+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Multiple blocking",
        "answer": "That Expedition cannot move forward.",
        "question": "If two different effects state that an Expedition  1. can only move forward due to {V} and  2. can only move forward due to {O}, what happens?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/ad153764a37f69aa460d",
        "id": "273",
        "fromDate": "2024-08-28T10:25:24+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "No moving in the arena",
        "answer": "In the Arena, Expeditions can't move forward nor backwards since there's only one region. Any such effect becomes irrelevant.",
        "question": "What's the effect of Will-o'-the-Wisp in the arena, during a tie-breaker Day?"
      }
    ]
  },
  "ALT_ALIZE_B_LY_45_C": {
    "@context": {
      "@vocab": "https://api.altered.gg/?_format=jsonld#",
      "hydra": "http://www.w3.org/ns/hydra/core#",
      "news": "CardHistoryData/news",
      "cardHistories": "CardHistoryData/cardHistories"
    },
    "@type": "CardHistoryData",
    "@id": "/.well-known/genid/b0611f676027a7fddf21",
    "news": {
      "@type": "CardHistory",
      "@id": "/.well-known/genid/7031f3c7c7ab6765251a",
      "id": "283",
      "fromDate": "2025-02-07T10:25:25+00:00",
      "type": "FUNCTIONAL_ERRATUM",
      "name": "Erratum of Icebound Tundra",
      "answer": "No.  Icebound Tundra will be updated in future printings to clarify it, previous wordings said:  When you play a Character in a region type where its base statistic is 0 — I gain a Trial counter.  Future printings will read:  When you play a Character — If it's in a terrain where its base statistic is 0, I gain 1 Trial counter. (The condition being after the — indicates that you check it at resolution).",
      "question": "If I play a Character with an ability that removes the Mountain terrain and a base stat of 0 in Mountain in a Mountain region , such as the Kraken or the Rare version of Persephone, does my Icebound Tundra gain a Trial counter?"
    },
    "cardHistories": [
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/24c4d61a977ee2879a48",
        "id": "285",
        "fromDate": "2025-03-09T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Choose not to sacrifice",
        "answer": "No. \"If you do\" doesn't mean you can choose, it means that if another effect prevents you from sacrificing the Icebound Landmark, you cannot create the Dragon Shade.",
        "question": "Can I choose not to sacrifice my Icebound Landmark when it gains a 3rd Trial counter?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/c2fde3025997000963d4",
        "id": "282",
        "fromDate": "2025-02-07T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Multiple zero",
        "answer": "Icebound Tundra only gains 1 counter per Character played.",
        "question": "If I play a Character in a region where two or more of its base statistics are zero (such as an Ouroubouros Trickster), how many counters does my Icebound Tundra gain ?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/7031f3c7c7ab6765251a",
        "id": "283",
        "fromDate": "2025-02-07T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "FUNCTIONAL_ERRATUM",
        "name": "Erratum of Icebound Tundra",
        "answer": "No.  Icebound Tundra will be updated in future printings to clarify it, previous wordings said:  When you play a Character in a region type where its base statistic is 0 — I gain a Trial counter.  Future printings will read:  When you play a Character — If it's in a terrain where its base statistic is 0, I gain 1 Trial counter. (The condition being after the — indicates that you check it at resolution).",
        "question": "If I play a Character with an ability that removes the Mountain terrain and a base stat of 0 in Mountain in a Mountain region , such as the Kraken or the Rare version of Persephone, does my Icebound Tundra gain a Trial counter?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/4251fb3710ecefca156a",
        "id": "284",
        "fromDate": "2025-01-31T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Sacrifice another way",
        "answer": "No. You only create the Dragon Shade when you successfully sacrifice the Icebound Landmark via its effect.",
        "question": "If I sacrifice an Icebound Landmark via another effect, such as (the Rare, Axiom version of) Boom!, can I create a Dragon Shade?"
      }
    ]
  },
  "ALT_ALIZE_B_LY_45_R1": {
    "@context": {
      "@vocab": "https://api.altered.gg/?_format=jsonld#",
      "hydra": "http://www.w3.org/ns/hydra/core#",
      "news": "CardHistoryData/news",
      "cardHistories": "CardHistoryData/cardHistories"
    },
    "@type": "CardHistoryData",
    "@id": "/.well-known/genid/9609d999f66551bd04fb",
    "news": {
      "@type": "CardHistory",
      "@id": "/.well-known/genid/9900499498d29a7697e0",
      "id": "283",
      "fromDate": "2025-02-07T10:25:25+00:00",
      "type": "FUNCTIONAL_ERRATUM",
      "name": "Erratum of Icebound Tundra",
      "answer": "No.  Icebound Tundra will be updated in future printings to clarify it, previous wordings said:  When you play a Character in a region type where its base statistic is 0 — I gain a Trial counter.  Future printings will read:  When you play a Character — If it's in a terrain where its base statistic is 0, I gain 1 Trial counter. (The condition being after the — indicates that you check it at resolution).",
      "question": "If I play a Character with an ability that removes the Mountain terrain and a base stat of 0 in Mountain in a Mountain region , such as the Kraken or the Rare version of Persephone, does my Icebound Tundra gain a Trial counter?"
    },
    "cardHistories": [
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/56024adab92849acbdf2",
        "id": "285",
        "fromDate": "2025-03-09T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Choose not to sacrifice",
        "answer": "No. \"If you do\" doesn't mean you can choose, it means that if another effect prevents you from sacrificing the Icebound Landmark, you cannot create the Dragon Shade.",
        "question": "Can I choose not to sacrifice my Icebound Landmark when it gains a 3rd Trial counter?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/2411af8c0cca436d0128",
        "id": "282",
        "fromDate": "2025-02-07T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Multiple zero",
        "answer": "Icebound Tundra only gains 1 counter per Character played.",
        "question": "If I play a Character in a region where two or more of its base statistics are zero (such as an Ouroubouros Trickster), how many counters does my Icebound Tundra gain ?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/9900499498d29a7697e0",
        "id": "283",
        "fromDate": "2025-02-07T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "FUNCTIONAL_ERRATUM",
        "name": "Erratum of Icebound Tundra",
        "answer": "No.  Icebound Tundra will be updated in future printings to clarify it, previous wordings said:  When you play a Character in a region type where its base statistic is 0 — I gain a Trial counter.  Future printings will read:  When you play a Character — If it's in a terrain where its base statistic is 0, I gain 1 Trial counter. (The condition being after the — indicates that you check it at resolution).",
        "question": "If I play a Character with an ability that removes the Mountain terrain and a base stat of 0 in Mountain in a Mountain region , such as the Kraken or the Rare version of Persephone, does my Icebound Tundra gain a Trial counter?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/b70dced6b900627732ce",
        "id": "284",
        "fromDate": "2025-01-31T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Sacrifice another way",
        "answer": "No. You only create the Dragon Shade when you successfully sacrifice the Icebound Landmark via its effect.",
        "question": "If I sacrifice an Icebound Landmark via another effect, such as (the Rare, Axiom version of) Boom!, can I create a Dragon Shade?"
      }
    ]
  },
  "ALT_ALIZE_B_MU_45_R2": {
    "@context": {
      "@vocab": "https://api.altered.gg/?_format=jsonld#",
      "hydra": "http://www.w3.org/ns/hydra/core#",
      "news": "CardHistoryData/news",
      "cardHistories": "CardHistoryData/cardHistories"
    },
    "@type": "CardHistoryData",
    "@id": "/.well-known/genid/bcbcef8036d812b079a6",
    "news": {
      "@type": "CardHistory",
      "@id": "/.well-known/genid/b0ba4dcaf22721c6e6da",
      "id": "311",
      "fromDate": "2025-02-05T10:25:25+00:00",
      "type": "FUNCTIONAL_ERRATUM",
      "name": "Erratum of Icebound Taiga",
      "answer": "Yes. The wording of Icebound Taiga has been updated to clarify it, previous wordings read:  \"When you play a Character in {V} — I gain a Trial counter.\"  Future printings will read:  \"When you play a Character — If it's in {V}, I gain 1 Trial counter.\" (The condition being after the — indicates that you check it at resolution).",
      "question": "If my Expedition is in a non-{V} region but I play a Character in it that turns it into {V}, such as Persephone, does my Icebound Taiga gain a Trial counter?"
    },
    "cardHistories": [
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/35302bfdcc039f3ad63b",
        "id": "312",
        "fromDate": "2025-03-09T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Choose not to sacrifice",
        "answer": "No. \"If you do\" doesn't mean you can choose, it means that if another effect prevents you from sacrificing the Icebound Landmark, you cannot create the Dragon Shade.",
        "question": "Can I choose not to sacrifice my Icebound Landmark when it gains a 3rd Trial counter?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/b0ba4dcaf22721c6e6da",
        "id": "311",
        "fromDate": "2025-02-05T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "FUNCTIONAL_ERRATUM",
        "name": "Erratum of Icebound Taiga",
        "answer": "Yes. The wording of Icebound Taiga has been updated to clarify it, previous wordings read:  \"When you play a Character in {V} — I gain a Trial counter.\"  Future printings will read:  \"When you play a Character — If it's in {V}, I gain 1 Trial counter.\" (The condition being after the — indicates that you check it at resolution).",
        "question": "If my Expedition is in a non-{V} region but I play a Character in it that turns it into {V}, such as Persephone, does my Icebound Taiga gain a Trial counter?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/f0e31f88d80cc1072c21",
        "id": "310",
        "fromDate": "2025-01-31T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Sacrifice another way",
        "answer": "No. You only create the Dragon Shade when you successfully sacrifice the Icebound Landmark via its effect.",
        "question": "If I sacrifice an Icebound Landmark via another effect, such as (the Rare, Axiom version of) Boom!, can I create a Dragon Shade?"
      }
    ]
  },
  "ALT_ALIZE_A_MU_45_C": {
    "@context": {
      "@vocab": "https://api.altered.gg/?_format=jsonld#",
      "hydra": "http://www.w3.org/ns/hydra/core#",
      "news": "CardHistoryData/news",
      "cardHistories": "CardHistoryData/cardHistories"
    },
    "@type": "CardHistoryData",
    "@id": "/.well-known/genid/fef5146a0a3ab4f6ecf2",
    "news": {
      "@type": "CardHistory",
      "@id": "/.well-known/genid/7ed94bda9f98c45c3c09",
      "id": "311",
      "fromDate": "2025-02-05T10:25:25+00:00",
      "type": "FUNCTIONAL_ERRATUM",
      "name": "Erratum of Icebound Taiga",
      "answer": "Yes. The wording of Icebound Taiga has been updated to clarify it, previous wordings read:  \"When you play a Character in {V} — I gain a Trial counter.\"  Future printings will read:  \"When you play a Character — If it's in {V}, I gain 1 Trial counter.\" (The condition being after the — indicates that you check it at resolution).",
      "question": "If my Expedition is in a non-{V} region but I play a Character in it that turns it into {V}, such as Persephone, does my Icebound Taiga gain a Trial counter?"
    },
    "cardHistories": [
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/1baa19c0d44c4452b446",
        "id": "312",
        "fromDate": "2025-03-09T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Choose not to sacrifice",
        "answer": "No. \"If you do\" doesn't mean you can choose, it means that if another effect prevents you from sacrificing the Icebound Landmark, you cannot create the Dragon Shade.",
        "question": "Can I choose not to sacrifice my Icebound Landmark when it gains a 3rd Trial counter?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/7ed94bda9f98c45c3c09",
        "id": "311",
        "fromDate": "2025-02-05T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "FUNCTIONAL_ERRATUM",
        "name": "Erratum of Icebound Taiga",
        "answer": "Yes. The wording of Icebound Taiga has been updated to clarify it, previous wordings read:  \"When you play a Character in {V} — I gain a Trial counter.\"  Future printings will read:  \"When you play a Character — If it's in {V}, I gain 1 Trial counter.\" (The condition being after the — indicates that you check it at resolution).",
        "question": "If my Expedition is in a non-{V} region but I play a Character in it that turns it into {V}, such as Persephone, does my Icebound Taiga gain a Trial counter?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/6ac89f4fd69f3d1fcada",
        "id": "310",
        "fromDate": "2025-01-31T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Sacrifice another way",
        "answer": "No. You only create the Dragon Shade when you successfully sacrifice the Icebound Landmark via its effect.",
        "question": "If I sacrifice an Icebound Landmark via another effect, such as (the Rare, Axiom version of) Boom!, can I create a Dragon Shade?"
      }
    ]
  },
  "ALT_ALIZE_A_MU_45_R1": {
    "@context": {
      "@vocab": "https://api.altered.gg/?_format=jsonld#",
      "hydra": "http://www.w3.org/ns/hydra/core#",
      "news": "CardHistoryData/news",
      "cardHistories": "CardHistoryData/cardHistories"
    },
    "@type": "CardHistoryData",
    "@id": "/.well-known/genid/1a19df3aa3e6e30433fd",
    "news": {
      "@type": "CardHistory",
      "@id": "/.well-known/genid/ee5b30492d22da6ac213",
      "id": "311",
      "fromDate": "2025-02-05T10:25:25+00:00",
      "type": "FUNCTIONAL_ERRATUM",
      "name": "Erratum of Icebound Taiga",
      "answer": "Yes. The wording of Icebound Taiga has been updated to clarify it, previous wordings read:  \"When you play a Character in {V} — I gain a Trial counter.\"  Future printings will read:  \"When you play a Character — If it's in {V}, I gain 1 Trial counter.\" (The condition being after the — indicates that you check it at resolution).",
      "question": "If my Expedition is in a non-{V} region but I play a Character in it that turns it into {V}, such as Persephone, does my Icebound Taiga gain a Trial counter?"
    },
    "cardHistories": [
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/a9b15da7f5a48c83cfdd",
        "id": "312",
        "fromDate": "2025-03-09T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Choose not to sacrifice",
        "answer": "No. \"If you do\" doesn't mean you can choose, it means that if another effect prevents you from sacrificing the Icebound Landmark, you cannot create the Dragon Shade.",
        "question": "Can I choose not to sacrifice my Icebound Landmark when it gains a 3rd Trial counter?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/ee5b30492d22da6ac213",
        "id": "311",
        "fromDate": "2025-02-05T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "FUNCTIONAL_ERRATUM",
        "name": "Erratum of Icebound Taiga",
        "answer": "Yes. The wording of Icebound Taiga has been updated to clarify it, previous wordings read:  \"When you play a Character in {V} — I gain a Trial counter.\"  Future printings will read:  \"When you play a Character — If it's in {V}, I gain 1 Trial counter.\" (The condition being after the — indicates that you check it at resolution).",
        "question": "If my Expedition is in a non-{V} region but I play a Character in it that turns it into {V}, such as Persephone, does my Icebound Taiga gain a Trial counter?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/4610dcb119b65f6ceed3",
        "id": "310",
        "fromDate": "2025-01-31T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Sacrifice another way",
        "answer": "No. You only create the Dragon Shade when you successfully sacrifice the Icebound Landmark via its effect.",
        "question": "If I sacrifice an Icebound Landmark via another effect, such as (the Rare, Axiom version of) Boom!, can I create a Dragon Shade?"
      }
    ]
  },
  "ALT_ALIZE_B_LY_35_R2": {
    "@context": {
      "@vocab": "https://api.altered.gg/?_format=jsonld#",
      "hydra": "http://www.w3.org/ns/hydra/core#",
      "news": "CardHistoryData/news",
      "cardHistories": "CardHistoryData/cardHistories"
    },
    "@type": "CardHistoryData",
    "@id": "/.well-known/genid/2923959a9dcfe5b156e7",
    "news": {
      "@type": "CardHistory",
      "@id": "/.well-known/genid/a6c71715cbbfcf1b3cf2",
      "id": "274",
      "fromDate": "2025-10-03T10:25:24+00:00",
      "type": "BALANCING_ERRATUM",
      "name": "Erratum of Will-o'-the-Wisp (Common & Rare)",
      "description": "https://www.altered.gg/en-us/news/skybound-odyssey-season-patch",
      "answer": "Yes. The first printing of Will-o'-the-Wisp (Lyra Version) said \"If the Expedition facing me is in {O}, it can only move forward due to {O}.\"  Future versions will say:  \"If an Expedition facing me is in {O}, it can't move forward DURING DUSK except due to {O}.\"  This change doesn't affect the Unique versions of Will-O-the-Wisp, which still prevent moving forward outside of Dusk.",
      "question": "Did the text of this card change?"
    },
    "cardHistories": [
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/b9adb7fe7921484b2162",
        "id": "276",
        "fromDate": "2025-10-03T10:25:24+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Move forward due to a Spell or another effect",
        "answer": "Yes. Note that as of October 2025, this is not true of the Common and Rare versions of Will'-O-the-Wisp, which only apply during Dusk.",
        "question": "If the Expedition facing it is in the proper terrain, does Will-O'-the-Wisp Unique prevent if from moving forward due to Small Step Giant Leap, Western Wind or similar abilities?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/a6c71715cbbfcf1b3cf2",
        "id": "274",
        "fromDate": "2025-10-03T10:25:24+00:00",
        "type": "BALANCING_ERRATUM",
        "name": "Erratum of Will-o'-the-Wisp (Common & Rare)",
        "description": "https://www.altered.gg/en-us/news/skybound-odyssey-season-patch",
        "answer": "Yes. The first printing of Will-o'-the-Wisp (Lyra Version) said \"If the Expedition facing me is in {O}, it can only move forward due to {O}.\"  Future versions will say:  \"If an Expedition facing me is in {O}, it can't move forward DURING DUSK except due to {O}.\"  This change doesn't affect the Unique versions of Will-O-the-Wisp, which still prevent moving forward outside of Dusk.",
        "question": "Did the text of this card change?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/a192ca9b70e7e982b8b6",
        "id": "275",
        "fromDate": "2025-10-03T10:25:24+00:00",
        "type": "BALANCING_ERRATUM",
        "name": "Erratum of Will-o'-the-Wisp (Common & Rare)",
        "description": "https://www.altered.gg/en-us/news/skybound-odyssey-season-patch",
        "answer": "Yes. The first printing of Will-o'-the-Wisp (Muna Version) said \"If the Expedition facing me is in {V}, it can only move forward due to {V}.\"  Future versions will say:  \"If an Expedition facing me is in {V}, it can't move forward DURING DUSK except due to {V}.\"  This change doesn't affect the Unique versions of Will-O-the-Wisp, which still prevent moving forward outside of Dusk.",
        "question": "Did the text of this card change?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/2b8e0894155f4634e531",
        "id": "268",
        "fromDate": "2025-10-03T10:25:24+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Moving forward a different way",
        "description": "https://www.altered.gg/en-us/news/skybound-odyssey-season-patch",
        "answer": "As of October 2025, the Common and Rare versions of Will-o'-the-Wisp only apply during Dusk. It does prevent an Expedition from moving forward due to anything else during that phase, but not during the rest of the Day (which is when such effects would typically happen).  The Unique versions of  Will-o'-the-Wisp still apply as long as they are in play.",
        "question": "If the Expedition facing Will-o'-the-Wisp (Rare, Muna version) is in {V}, can it still move forward due to effects such as Small Step, Giant Leap?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/3d942d32e412a70a7501",
        "id": "267",
        "fromDate": "2025-02-03T10:25:24+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Blocking Magic Sleigh",
        "answer": "The Expedition moves forward two regions in one single step, Will-o-the-wisp cannot block it in the middle. (Of course it can prevent it from moving altogether if the starting region is the proper terrain.)",
        "question": "If the Expedition facing Will-o-the-Wisp moves forward, and contains a card such as The Magic Sleigh, allowing it to move two regions instead of one, what happens? Can it be blocked if the first move brings it in {V}?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/80bcf5127ebbb3ad9e5b",
        "id": "270",
        "fromDate": "2025-02-03T10:25:24+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Multiple blocking",
        "answer": "That Expedition cannot move forward.",
        "question": "If two different effects state that an Expedition  1. can only move forward due to {V} and  2. can only move forward due to {O}, what happens?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/3692b2496a168ed638f6",
        "id": "272",
        "fromDate": "2025-02-03T10:25:24+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Gigantic Will'o'-the-wisp",
        "answer": "For a Gigantic Character, \"the Expedition facing me\" means \"the Expeditions facing me\". In the specific case of Gigantic Will-o-the-Wisp (Rare, Muna version), their effect means \"If any Expedition facing me is in {V}, that Expedition cannot move forward except due to {V}.\" (They don't need to both be in {V}).",
        "question": "If Will-o'-the-Wisp or a similar card becomes Gigantic (for example due to Eat Me Energy Bars), how does it affect the Expeditions facing it?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/daee8f90ffdfcf3fb0e5",
        "id": "273",
        "fromDate": "2024-08-28T10:25:24+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "No moving in the arena",
        "answer": "In the Arena, Expeditions can't move forward nor backwards since there's only one region. Any such effect becomes irrelevant.",
        "question": "What's the effect of Will-o'-the-Wisp in the arena, during a tie-breaker Day?"
      }
    ]
  },
  "ALT_ALIZE_B_MU_45_C": {
    "@context": {
      "@vocab": "https://api.altered.gg/?_format=jsonld#",
      "hydra": "http://www.w3.org/ns/hydra/core#",
      "news": "CardHistoryData/news",
      "cardHistories": "CardHistoryData/cardHistories"
    },
    "@type": "CardHistoryData",
    "@id": "/.well-known/genid/dc0d3a93dba86c674a68",
    "news": {
      "@type": "CardHistory",
      "@id": "/.well-known/genid/fae7783b96ef95f9a9d5",
      "id": "311",
      "fromDate": "2025-02-05T10:25:25+00:00",
      "type": "FUNCTIONAL_ERRATUM",
      "name": "Erratum of Icebound Taiga",
      "answer": "Yes. The wording of Icebound Taiga has been updated to clarify it, previous wordings read:  \"When you play a Character in {V} — I gain a Trial counter.\"  Future printings will read:  \"When you play a Character — If it's in {V}, I gain 1 Trial counter.\" (The condition being after the — indicates that you check it at resolution).",
      "question": "If my Expedition is in a non-{V} region but I play a Character in it that turns it into {V}, such as Persephone, does my Icebound Taiga gain a Trial counter?"
    },
    "cardHistories": [
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/b20f95e8e4bf1f3288fa",
        "id": "312",
        "fromDate": "2025-03-09T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Choose not to sacrifice",
        "answer": "No. \"If you do\" doesn't mean you can choose, it means that if another effect prevents you from sacrificing the Icebound Landmark, you cannot create the Dragon Shade.",
        "question": "Can I choose not to sacrifice my Icebound Landmark when it gains a 3rd Trial counter?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/fae7783b96ef95f9a9d5",
        "id": "311",
        "fromDate": "2025-02-05T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "FUNCTIONAL_ERRATUM",
        "name": "Erratum of Icebound Taiga",
        "answer": "Yes. The wording of Icebound Taiga has been updated to clarify it, previous wordings read:  \"When you play a Character in {V} — I gain a Trial counter.\"  Future printings will read:  \"When you play a Character — If it's in {V}, I gain 1 Trial counter.\" (The condition being after the — indicates that you check it at resolution).",
        "question": "If my Expedition is in a non-{V} region but I play a Character in it that turns it into {V}, such as Persephone, does my Icebound Taiga gain a Trial counter?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/48e3181ad50e40099bf5",
        "id": "310",
        "fromDate": "2025-01-31T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Sacrifice another way",
        "answer": "No. You only create the Dragon Shade when you successfully sacrifice the Icebound Landmark via its effect.",
        "question": "If I sacrifice an Icebound Landmark via another effect, such as (the Rare, Axiom version of) Boom!, can I create a Dragon Shade?"
      }
    ]
  },
  "ALT_ALIZE_B_MU_45_R1": {
    "@context": {
      "@vocab": "https://api.altered.gg/?_format=jsonld#",
      "hydra": "http://www.w3.org/ns/hydra/core#",
      "news": "CardHistoryData/news",
      "cardHistories": "CardHistoryData/cardHistories"
    },
    "@type": "CardHistoryData",
    "@id": "/.well-known/genid/3a48b31143e94e631683",
    "news": {
      "@type": "CardHistory",
      "@id": "/.well-known/genid/3d34189b6082e1984dbd",
      "id": "311",
      "fromDate": "2025-02-05T10:25:25+00:00",
      "type": "FUNCTIONAL_ERRATUM",
      "name": "Erratum of Icebound Taiga",
      "answer": "Yes. The wording of Icebound Taiga has been updated to clarify it, previous wordings read:  \"When you play a Character in {V} — I gain a Trial counter.\"  Future printings will read:  \"When you play a Character — If it's in {V}, I gain 1 Trial counter.\" (The condition being after the — indicates that you check it at resolution).",
      "question": "If my Expedition is in a non-{V} region but I play a Character in it that turns it into {V}, such as Persephone, does my Icebound Taiga gain a Trial counter?"
    },
    "cardHistories": [
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/bf6fc3471132a5fae242",
        "id": "312",
        "fromDate": "2025-03-09T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Choose not to sacrifice",
        "answer": "No. \"If you do\" doesn't mean you can choose, it means that if another effect prevents you from sacrificing the Icebound Landmark, you cannot create the Dragon Shade.",
        "question": "Can I choose not to sacrifice my Icebound Landmark when it gains a 3rd Trial counter?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/3d34189b6082e1984dbd",
        "id": "311",
        "fromDate": "2025-02-05T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "FUNCTIONAL_ERRATUM",
        "name": "Erratum of Icebound Taiga",
        "answer": "Yes. The wording of Icebound Taiga has been updated to clarify it, previous wordings read:  \"When you play a Character in {V} — I gain a Trial counter.\"  Future printings will read:  \"When you play a Character — If it's in {V}, I gain 1 Trial counter.\" (The condition being after the — indicates that you check it at resolution).",
        "question": "If my Expedition is in a non-{V} region but I play a Character in it that turns it into {V}, such as Persephone, does my Icebound Taiga gain a Trial counter?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/12147373fcc0ede3dcb4",
        "id": "310",
        "fromDate": "2025-01-31T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Sacrifice another way",
        "answer": "No. You only create the Dragon Shade when you successfully sacrifice the Icebound Landmark via its effect.",
        "question": "If I sacrifice an Icebound Landmark via another effect, such as (the Rare, Axiom version of) Boom!, can I create a Dragon Shade?"
      }
    ]
  },
  "ALT_ALIZE_A_OR_47_C": {
    "@context": {
      "@vocab": "https://api.altered.gg/?_format=jsonld#",
      "hydra": "http://www.w3.org/ns/hydra/core#",
      "news": "CardHistoryData/news",
      "cardHistories": "CardHistoryData/cardHistories"
    },
    "@type": "CardHistoryData",
    "@id": "/.well-known/genid/8d938b0a596e18d71684",
    "news": {
      "@type": "CardHistory",
      "@id": "/.well-known/genid/05acdfb1f4b857b8d6ca",
      "id": "322",
      "fromDate": "2025-02-18T10:25:25+00:00",
      "type": "FUNCTIONAL_ERRATUM",
      "name": "Only by playing characters",
      "answer": "No. The first printing of Icebound Lake said \"When a non-token Character joins one of your Expeditions, if it's behind — I gain a Trial counter.  When I gain my third Trial counter — Sacrifice me. If you do, create a [Dragon Shade 5/5/5] Illusion token in target Expedition, then target Character gains [Asleep].\"  Future printings will say \"When you play a Character — If its Expedition is behind, I gain 1 Trial counter.  When I gain my third Trial counter — Sacrifice me. If you do, create a [Dragon Shade 5/5/5] Illusion token in target Expedition, then target Character gains [Asleep].\"",
      "question": "If a Character I control switches Expedition, and ends up in an Expedition that's behind, do I gain a Trial counter?"
    },
    "cardHistories": [
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/b136183038839945cd65",
        "id": "325",
        "fromDate": "2025-03-09T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Choose not to sacrifice",
        "answer": "No. \"If you do\" doesn't mean you can choose, it means that if another effect prevents you from sacrificing the Icebound Landmark, you cannot create the Dragon Shade.",
        "question": "Can I choose not to sacrifice my Icebound Landmark when it gains a 3rd Trial counter?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/05acdfb1f4b857b8d6ca",
        "id": "322",
        "fromDate": "2025-02-18T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "FUNCTIONAL_ERRATUM",
        "name": "Only by playing characters",
        "answer": "No. The first printing of Icebound Lake said \"When a non-token Character joins one of your Expeditions, if it's behind — I gain a Trial counter.  When I gain my third Trial counter — Sacrifice me. If you do, create a [Dragon Shade 5/5/5] Illusion token in target Expedition, then target Character gains [Asleep].\"  Future printings will say \"When you play a Character — If its Expedition is behind, I gain 1 Trial counter.  When I gain my third Trial counter — Sacrifice me. If you do, create a [Dragon Shade 5/5/5] Illusion token in target Expedition, then target Character gains [Asleep].\"",
        "question": "If a Character I control switches Expedition, and ends up in an Expedition that's behind, do I gain a Trial counter?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/5aec9d2616c057bc8455",
        "id": "323",
        "fromDate": "2025-02-18T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Tokens are not played",
        "answer": "No. You do not play a token, you play a card (or activate an ability) that creates them.",
        "question": "If I create a token in an Expedition that's behind, do I gain 1 Trial counter?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/922258ed3196cbba75c7",
        "id": "324",
        "fromDate": "2025-01-31T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Sacrifice another way",
        "answer": "No. You only create the Dragon Shade when you successfully sacrifice the Icebound Landmark via its effect.",
        "question": "If I sacrifice an Icebound Landmark via another effect, such as (the Rare, Axiom version of) Boom!, can I create a Dragon Shade?"
      }
    ]
  },
  "ALT_ALIZE_A_OR_47_R1": {
    "@context": {
      "@vocab": "https://api.altered.gg/?_format=jsonld#",
      "hydra": "http://www.w3.org/ns/hydra/core#",
      "news": "CardHistoryData/news",
      "cardHistories": "CardHistoryData/cardHistories"
    },
    "@type": "CardHistoryData",
    "@id": "/.well-known/genid/1167b517ec6c10d8a2a4",
    "news": {
      "@type": "CardHistory",
      "@id": "/.well-known/genid/c585e2d6a5d0fdb2b283",
      "id": "322",
      "fromDate": "2025-02-18T10:25:25+00:00",
      "type": "FUNCTIONAL_ERRATUM",
      "name": "Only by playing characters",
      "answer": "No. The first printing of Icebound Lake said \"When a non-token Character joins one of your Expeditions, if it's behind — I gain a Trial counter.  When I gain my third Trial counter — Sacrifice me. If you do, create a [Dragon Shade 5/5/5] Illusion token in target Expedition, then target Character gains [Asleep].\"  Future printings will say \"When you play a Character — If its Expedition is behind, I gain 1 Trial counter.  When I gain my third Trial counter — Sacrifice me. If you do, create a [Dragon Shade 5/5/5] Illusion token in target Expedition, then target Character gains [Asleep].\"",
      "question": "If a Character I control switches Expedition, and ends up in an Expedition that's behind, do I gain a Trial counter?"
    },
    "cardHistories": [
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/5149599e3a5e1f7bc195",
        "id": "325",
        "fromDate": "2025-03-09T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Choose not to sacrifice",
        "answer": "No. \"If you do\" doesn't mean you can choose, it means that if another effect prevents you from sacrificing the Icebound Landmark, you cannot create the Dragon Shade.",
        "question": "Can I choose not to sacrifice my Icebound Landmark when it gains a 3rd Trial counter?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/c585e2d6a5d0fdb2b283",
        "id": "322",
        "fromDate": "2025-02-18T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "FUNCTIONAL_ERRATUM",
        "name": "Only by playing characters",
        "answer": "No. The first printing of Icebound Lake said \"When a non-token Character joins one of your Expeditions, if it's behind — I gain a Trial counter.  When I gain my third Trial counter — Sacrifice me. If you do, create a [Dragon Shade 5/5/5] Illusion token in target Expedition, then target Character gains [Asleep].\"  Future printings will say \"When you play a Character — If its Expedition is behind, I gain 1 Trial counter.  When I gain my third Trial counter — Sacrifice me. If you do, create a [Dragon Shade 5/5/5] Illusion token in target Expedition, then target Character gains [Asleep].\"",
        "question": "If a Character I control switches Expedition, and ends up in an Expedition that's behind, do I gain a Trial counter?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/766643321b0c7dd57d82",
        "id": "323",
        "fromDate": "2025-02-18T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Tokens are not played",
        "answer": "No. You do not play a token, you play a card (or activate an ability) that creates them.",
        "question": "If I create a token in an Expedition that's behind, do I gain 1 Trial counter?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/4de5575b85a72295580a",
        "id": "324",
        "fromDate": "2025-01-31T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Sacrifice another way",
        "answer": "No. You only create the Dragon Shade when you successfully sacrifice the Icebound Landmark via its effect.",
        "question": "If I sacrifice an Icebound Landmark via another effect, such as (the Rare, Axiom version of) Boom!, can I create a Dragon Shade?"
      }
    ]
  },
  "ALT_ALIZE_B_OR_47_C": {
    "@context": {
      "@vocab": "https://api.altered.gg/?_format=jsonld#",
      "hydra": "http://www.w3.org/ns/hydra/core#",
      "news": "CardHistoryData/news",
      "cardHistories": "CardHistoryData/cardHistories"
    },
    "@type": "CardHistoryData",
    "@id": "/.well-known/genid/17aefe320123cc3fa7e8",
    "news": {
      "@type": "CardHistory",
      "@id": "/.well-known/genid/f233e59ae8499338d7a6",
      "id": "322",
      "fromDate": "2025-02-18T10:25:25+00:00",
      "type": "FUNCTIONAL_ERRATUM",
      "name": "Only by playing characters",
      "answer": "No. The first printing of Icebound Lake said \"When a non-token Character joins one of your Expeditions, if it's behind — I gain a Trial counter.  When I gain my third Trial counter — Sacrifice me. If you do, create a [Dragon Shade 5/5/5] Illusion token in target Expedition, then target Character gains [Asleep].\"  Future printings will say \"When you play a Character — If its Expedition is behind, I gain 1 Trial counter.  When I gain my third Trial counter — Sacrifice me. If you do, create a [Dragon Shade 5/5/5] Illusion token in target Expedition, then target Character gains [Asleep].\"",
      "question": "If a Character I control switches Expedition, and ends up in an Expedition that's behind, do I gain a Trial counter?"
    },
    "cardHistories": [
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/d41e048388f051ecb735",
        "id": "325",
        "fromDate": "2025-03-09T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Choose not to sacrifice",
        "answer": "No. \"If you do\" doesn't mean you can choose, it means that if another effect prevents you from sacrificing the Icebound Landmark, you cannot create the Dragon Shade.",
        "question": "Can I choose not to sacrifice my Icebound Landmark when it gains a 3rd Trial counter?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/f233e59ae8499338d7a6",
        "id": "322",
        "fromDate": "2025-02-18T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "FUNCTIONAL_ERRATUM",
        "name": "Only by playing characters",
        "answer": "No. The first printing of Icebound Lake said \"When a non-token Character joins one of your Expeditions, if it's behind — I gain a Trial counter.  When I gain my third Trial counter — Sacrifice me. If you do, create a [Dragon Shade 5/5/5] Illusion token in target Expedition, then target Character gains [Asleep].\"  Future printings will say \"When you play a Character — If its Expedition is behind, I gain 1 Trial counter.  When I gain my third Trial counter — Sacrifice me. If you do, create a [Dragon Shade 5/5/5] Illusion token in target Expedition, then target Character gains [Asleep].\"",
        "question": "If a Character I control switches Expedition, and ends up in an Expedition that's behind, do I gain a Trial counter?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/5912cac781b30f4838e1",
        "id": "323",
        "fromDate": "2025-02-18T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Tokens are not played",
        "answer": "No. You do not play a token, you play a card (or activate an ability) that creates them.",
        "question": "If I create a token in an Expedition that's behind, do I gain 1 Trial counter?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/8dbab29ee8f6303afa98",
        "id": "324",
        "fromDate": "2025-01-31T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Sacrifice another way",
        "answer": "No. You only create the Dragon Shade when you successfully sacrifice the Icebound Landmark via its effect.",
        "question": "If I sacrifice an Icebound Landmark via another effect, such as (the Rare, Axiom version of) Boom!, can I create a Dragon Shade?"
      }
    ]
  },
  "ALT_ALIZE_B_OR_47_R1": {
    "@context": {
      "@vocab": "https://api.altered.gg/?_format=jsonld#",
      "hydra": "http://www.w3.org/ns/hydra/core#",
      "news": "CardHistoryData/news",
      "cardHistories": "CardHistoryData/cardHistories"
    },
    "@type": "CardHistoryData",
    "@id": "/.well-known/genid/234758f4d4eace2de7c5",
    "news": {
      "@type": "CardHistory",
      "@id": "/.well-known/genid/d9610409ce7bd8e4afa0",
      "id": "322",
      "fromDate": "2025-02-18T10:25:25+00:00",
      "type": "FUNCTIONAL_ERRATUM",
      "name": "Only by playing characters",
      "answer": "No. The first printing of Icebound Lake said \"When a non-token Character joins one of your Expeditions, if it's behind — I gain a Trial counter.  When I gain my third Trial counter — Sacrifice me. If you do, create a [Dragon Shade 5/5/5] Illusion token in target Expedition, then target Character gains [Asleep].\"  Future printings will say \"When you play a Character — If its Expedition is behind, I gain 1 Trial counter.  When I gain my third Trial counter — Sacrifice me. If you do, create a [Dragon Shade 5/5/5] Illusion token in target Expedition, then target Character gains [Asleep].\"",
      "question": "If a Character I control switches Expedition, and ends up in an Expedition that's behind, do I gain a Trial counter?"
    },
    "cardHistories": [
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/bc58ee7ffa420ea98836",
        "id": "325",
        "fromDate": "2025-03-09T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Choose not to sacrifice",
        "answer": "No. \"If you do\" doesn't mean you can choose, it means that if another effect prevents you from sacrificing the Icebound Landmark, you cannot create the Dragon Shade.",
        "question": "Can I choose not to sacrifice my Icebound Landmark when it gains a 3rd Trial counter?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/d9610409ce7bd8e4afa0",
        "id": "322",
        "fromDate": "2025-02-18T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "FUNCTIONAL_ERRATUM",
        "name": "Only by playing characters",
        "answer": "No. The first printing of Icebound Lake said \"When a non-token Character joins one of your Expeditions, if it's behind — I gain a Trial counter.  When I gain my third Trial counter — Sacrifice me. If you do, create a [Dragon Shade 5/5/5] Illusion token in target Expedition, then target Character gains [Asleep].\"  Future printings will say \"When you play a Character — If its Expedition is behind, I gain 1 Trial counter.  When I gain my third Trial counter — Sacrifice me. If you do, create a [Dragon Shade 5/5/5] Illusion token in target Expedition, then target Character gains [Asleep].\"",
        "question": "If a Character I control switches Expedition, and ends up in an Expedition that's behind, do I gain a Trial counter?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/712035d6632cb450760a",
        "id": "323",
        "fromDate": "2025-02-18T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Tokens are not played",
        "answer": "No. You do not play a token, you play a card (or activate an ability) that creates them.",
        "question": "If I create a token in an Expedition that's behind, do I gain 1 Trial counter?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/cfb843772e7627fe8ae7",
        "id": "324",
        "fromDate": "2025-01-31T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Sacrifice another way",
        "answer": "No. You only create the Dragon Shade when you successfully sacrifice the Icebound Landmark via its effect.",
        "question": "If I sacrifice an Icebound Landmark via another effect, such as (the Rare, Axiom version of) Boom!, can I create a Dragon Shade?"
      }
    ]
  },
  "ALT_ALIZE_A_LY_45_R2": {
    "@context": {
      "@vocab": "https://api.altered.gg/?_format=jsonld#",
      "hydra": "http://www.w3.org/ns/hydra/core#",
      "news": "CardHistoryData/news",
      "cardHistories": "CardHistoryData/cardHistories"
    },
    "@type": "CardHistoryData",
    "@id": "/.well-known/genid/d0e5954a6bc642a9471b",
    "news": {
      "@type": "CardHistory",
      "@id": "/.well-known/genid/39117e93687fe61b4a7c",
      "id": "283",
      "fromDate": "2025-02-07T10:25:25+00:00",
      "type": "FUNCTIONAL_ERRATUM",
      "name": "Erratum of Icebound Tundra",
      "answer": "No.  Icebound Tundra will be updated in future printings to clarify it, previous wordings said:  When you play a Character in a region type where its base statistic is 0 — I gain a Trial counter.  Future printings will read:  When you play a Character — If it's in a terrain where its base statistic is 0, I gain 1 Trial counter. (The condition being after the — indicates that you check it at resolution).",
      "question": "If I play a Character with an ability that removes the Mountain terrain and a base stat of 0 in Mountain in a Mountain region , such as the Kraken or the Rare version of Persephone, does my Icebound Tundra gain a Trial counter?"
    },
    "cardHistories": [
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/5fbda4de1f63fb044198",
        "id": "285",
        "fromDate": "2025-03-09T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Choose not to sacrifice",
        "answer": "No. \"If you do\" doesn't mean you can choose, it means that if another effect prevents you from sacrificing the Icebound Landmark, you cannot create the Dragon Shade.",
        "question": "Can I choose not to sacrifice my Icebound Landmark when it gains a 3rd Trial counter?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/67f3d688c8f1cfe44393",
        "id": "282",
        "fromDate": "2025-02-07T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Multiple zero",
        "answer": "Icebound Tundra only gains 1 counter per Character played.",
        "question": "If I play a Character in a region where two or more of its base statistics are zero (such as an Ouroubouros Trickster), how many counters does my Icebound Tundra gain ?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/39117e93687fe61b4a7c",
        "id": "283",
        "fromDate": "2025-02-07T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "FUNCTIONAL_ERRATUM",
        "name": "Erratum of Icebound Tundra",
        "answer": "No.  Icebound Tundra will be updated in future printings to clarify it, previous wordings said:  When you play a Character in a region type where its base statistic is 0 — I gain a Trial counter.  Future printings will read:  When you play a Character — If it's in a terrain where its base statistic is 0, I gain 1 Trial counter. (The condition being after the — indicates that you check it at resolution).",
        "question": "If I play a Character with an ability that removes the Mountain terrain and a base stat of 0 in Mountain in a Mountain region , such as the Kraken or the Rare version of Persephone, does my Icebound Tundra gain a Trial counter?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/d50a037e6913d104ce42",
        "id": "284",
        "fromDate": "2025-01-31T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Sacrifice another way",
        "answer": "No. You only create the Dragon Shade when you successfully sacrifice the Icebound Landmark via its effect.",
        "question": "If I sacrifice an Icebound Landmark via another effect, such as (the Rare, Axiom version of) Boom!, can I create a Dragon Shade?"
      }
    ]
  },
  "ALT_ALIZE_A_OR_47_R2": {
    "@context": {
      "@vocab": "https://api.altered.gg/?_format=jsonld#",
      "hydra": "http://www.w3.org/ns/hydra/core#",
      "news": "CardHistoryData/news",
      "cardHistories": "CardHistoryData/cardHistories"
    },
    "@type": "CardHistoryData",
    "@id": "/.well-known/genid/0a043ac0fea0d418d8ca",
    "news": {
      "@type": "CardHistory",
      "@id": "/.well-known/genid/f66bbb906c6285ac0ad3",
      "id": "322",
      "fromDate": "2025-02-18T10:25:25+00:00",
      "type": "FUNCTIONAL_ERRATUM",
      "name": "Only by playing characters",
      "answer": "No. The first printing of Icebound Lake said \"When a non-token Character joins one of your Expeditions, if it's behind — I gain a Trial counter.  When I gain my third Trial counter — Sacrifice me. If you do, create a [Dragon Shade 5/5/5] Illusion token in target Expedition, then target Character gains [Asleep].\"  Future printings will say \"When you play a Character — If its Expedition is behind, I gain 1 Trial counter.  When I gain my third Trial counter — Sacrifice me. If you do, create a [Dragon Shade 5/5/5] Illusion token in target Expedition, then target Character gains [Asleep].\"",
      "question": "If a Character I control switches Expedition, and ends up in an Expedition that's behind, do I gain a Trial counter?"
    },
    "cardHistories": [
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/35232d9679a994e71848",
        "id": "325",
        "fromDate": "2025-03-09T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Choose not to sacrifice",
        "answer": "No. \"If you do\" doesn't mean you can choose, it means that if another effect prevents you from sacrificing the Icebound Landmark, you cannot create the Dragon Shade.",
        "question": "Can I choose not to sacrifice my Icebound Landmark when it gains a 3rd Trial counter?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/f66bbb906c6285ac0ad3",
        "id": "322",
        "fromDate": "2025-02-18T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "FUNCTIONAL_ERRATUM",
        "name": "Only by playing characters",
        "answer": "No. The first printing of Icebound Lake said \"When a non-token Character joins one of your Expeditions, if it's behind — I gain a Trial counter.  When I gain my third Trial counter — Sacrifice me. If you do, create a [Dragon Shade 5/5/5] Illusion token in target Expedition, then target Character gains [Asleep].\"  Future printings will say \"When you play a Character — If its Expedition is behind, I gain 1 Trial counter.  When I gain my third Trial counter — Sacrifice me. If you do, create a [Dragon Shade 5/5/5] Illusion token in target Expedition, then target Character gains [Asleep].\"",
        "question": "If a Character I control switches Expedition, and ends up in an Expedition that's behind, do I gain a Trial counter?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/8ab16144fbde7fc6924f",
        "id": "323",
        "fromDate": "2025-02-18T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Tokens are not played",
        "answer": "No. You do not play a token, you play a card (or activate an ability) that creates them.",
        "question": "If I create a token in an Expedition that's behind, do I gain 1 Trial counter?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/ea499af0d9bd5fd6b509",
        "id": "324",
        "fromDate": "2025-01-31T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Sacrifice another way",
        "answer": "No. You only create the Dragon Shade when you successfully sacrifice the Icebound Landmark via its effect.",
        "question": "If I sacrifice an Icebound Landmark via another effect, such as (the Rare, Axiom version of) Boom!, can I create a Dragon Shade?"
      }
    ]
  },
  "ALT_ALIZE_B_LY_45_R2": {
    "@context": {
      "@vocab": "https://api.altered.gg/?_format=jsonld#",
      "hydra": "http://www.w3.org/ns/hydra/core#",
      "news": "CardHistoryData/news",
      "cardHistories": "CardHistoryData/cardHistories"
    },
    "@type": "CardHistoryData",
    "@id": "/.well-known/genid/5e2640bba111acd131b2",
    "news": {
      "@type": "CardHistory",
      "@id": "/.well-known/genid/747a2755a4126d9f8fb3",
      "id": "283",
      "fromDate": "2025-02-07T10:25:25+00:00",
      "type": "FUNCTIONAL_ERRATUM",
      "name": "Erratum of Icebound Tundra",
      "answer": "No.  Icebound Tundra will be updated in future printings to clarify it, previous wordings said:  When you play a Character in a region type where its base statistic is 0 — I gain a Trial counter.  Future printings will read:  When you play a Character — If it's in a terrain where its base statistic is 0, I gain 1 Trial counter. (The condition being after the — indicates that you check it at resolution).",
      "question": "If I play a Character with an ability that removes the Mountain terrain and a base stat of 0 in Mountain in a Mountain region , such as the Kraken or the Rare version of Persephone, does my Icebound Tundra gain a Trial counter?"
    },
    "cardHistories": [
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/493bc47dc854bdadaeb1",
        "id": "285",
        "fromDate": "2025-03-09T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Choose not to sacrifice",
        "answer": "No. \"If you do\" doesn't mean you can choose, it means that if another effect prevents you from sacrificing the Icebound Landmark, you cannot create the Dragon Shade.",
        "question": "Can I choose not to sacrifice my Icebound Landmark when it gains a 3rd Trial counter?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/0e1e06d3e2971835caeb",
        "id": "282",
        "fromDate": "2025-02-07T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Multiple zero",
        "answer": "Icebound Tundra only gains 1 counter per Character played.",
        "question": "If I play a Character in a region where two or more of its base statistics are zero (such as an Ouroubouros Trickster), how many counters does my Icebound Tundra gain ?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/747a2755a4126d9f8fb3",
        "id": "283",
        "fromDate": "2025-02-07T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "FUNCTIONAL_ERRATUM",
        "name": "Erratum of Icebound Tundra",
        "answer": "No.  Icebound Tundra will be updated in future printings to clarify it, previous wordings said:  When you play a Character in a region type where its base statistic is 0 — I gain a Trial counter.  Future printings will read:  When you play a Character — If it's in a terrain where its base statistic is 0, I gain 1 Trial counter. (The condition being after the — indicates that you check it at resolution).",
        "question": "If I play a Character with an ability that removes the Mountain terrain and a base stat of 0 in Mountain in a Mountain region , such as the Kraken or the Rare version of Persephone, does my Icebound Tundra gain a Trial counter?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/117918959b562020f1bc",
        "id": "284",
        "fromDate": "2025-01-31T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Sacrifice another way",
        "answer": "No. You only create the Dragon Shade when you successfully sacrifice the Icebound Landmark via its effect.",
        "question": "If I sacrifice an Icebound Landmark via another effect, such as (the Rare, Axiom version of) Boom!, can I create a Dragon Shade?"
      }
    ]
  },
  "ALT_ALIZE_B_OR_47_R2": {
    "@context": {
      "@vocab": "https://api.altered.gg/?_format=jsonld#",
      "hydra": "http://www.w3.org/ns/hydra/core#",
      "news": "CardHistoryData/news",
      "cardHistories": "CardHistoryData/cardHistories"
    },
    "@type": "CardHistoryData",
    "@id": "/.well-known/genid/fdd12962a3b84a60152a",
    "news": {
      "@type": "CardHistory",
      "@id": "/.well-known/genid/c7469e10ffe1ad91fe5c",
      "id": "322",
      "fromDate": "2025-02-18T10:25:25+00:00",
      "type": "FUNCTIONAL_ERRATUM",
      "name": "Only by playing characters",
      "answer": "No. The first printing of Icebound Lake said \"When a non-token Character joins one of your Expeditions, if it's behind — I gain a Trial counter.  When I gain my third Trial counter — Sacrifice me. If you do, create a [Dragon Shade 5/5/5] Illusion token in target Expedition, then target Character gains [Asleep].\"  Future printings will say \"When you play a Character — If its Expedition is behind, I gain 1 Trial counter.  When I gain my third Trial counter — Sacrifice me. If you do, create a [Dragon Shade 5/5/5] Illusion token in target Expedition, then target Character gains [Asleep].\"",
      "question": "If a Character I control switches Expedition, and ends up in an Expedition that's behind, do I gain a Trial counter?"
    },
    "cardHistories": [
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/6da88902ad6e4ca737f9",
        "id": "325",
        "fromDate": "2025-03-09T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Choose not to sacrifice",
        "answer": "No. \"If you do\" doesn't mean you can choose, it means that if another effect prevents you from sacrificing the Icebound Landmark, you cannot create the Dragon Shade.",
        "question": "Can I choose not to sacrifice my Icebound Landmark when it gains a 3rd Trial counter?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/c7469e10ffe1ad91fe5c",
        "id": "322",
        "fromDate": "2025-02-18T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "FUNCTIONAL_ERRATUM",
        "name": "Only by playing characters",
        "answer": "No. The first printing of Icebound Lake said \"When a non-token Character joins one of your Expeditions, if it's behind — I gain a Trial counter.  When I gain my third Trial counter — Sacrifice me. If you do, create a [Dragon Shade 5/5/5] Illusion token in target Expedition, then target Character gains [Asleep].\"  Future printings will say \"When you play a Character — If its Expedition is behind, I gain 1 Trial counter.  When I gain my third Trial counter — Sacrifice me. If you do, create a [Dragon Shade 5/5/5] Illusion token in target Expedition, then target Character gains [Asleep].\"",
        "question": "If a Character I control switches Expedition, and ends up in an Expedition that's behind, do I gain a Trial counter?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/d104d0e704f465733242",
        "id": "323",
        "fromDate": "2025-02-18T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Tokens are not played",
        "answer": "No. You do not play a token, you play a card (or activate an ability) that creates them.",
        "question": "If I create a token in an Expedition that's behind, do I gain 1 Trial counter?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/2bafaefbc720b861834b",
        "id": "324",
        "fromDate": "2025-01-31T10:25:25+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Sacrifice another way",
        "answer": "No. You only create the Dragon Shade when you successfully sacrifice the Icebound Landmark via its effect.",
        "question": "If I sacrifice an Icebound Landmark via another effect, such as (the Rare, Axiom version of) Boom!, can I create a Dragon Shade?"
      }
    ]
  },
  "ALT_ALIZE_B_YZ_03_C": {
    "@context": {
      "@vocab": "https://api.altered.gg/?_format=jsonld#",
      "hydra": "http://www.w3.org/ns/hydra/core#",
      "news": "CardHistoryData/news",
      "cardHistories": "CardHistoryData/cardHistories"
    },
    "@type": "CardHistoryData",
    "@id": "/.well-known/genid/b9e8a80a8b4a15093c6f",
    "news": {
      "@type": "CardHistory",
      "@id": "/.well-known/genid/2b165d6a63e53fca7e29",
      "id": "180",
      "fromDate": "2025-08-11T10:25:23+00:00",
      "type": "BALANCING_ERRATUM",
      "name": "Balancing Erratum of Afanas",
      "description": "https://www.altered.gg/news/whispers-from-the-maze-mid-season-patch",
      "answer": "Yes. The first printing of this card said:  \"When you play a Spell — Target Character you control gains 1 boost. (Do this after the spell resolves.)\"  Future versions will say:  \"Spells you play with Hand Cost {1} or less have [Fleeting].  When you play a Spell — Target Character you control gains 1 boost. (Do this after the spell resolves.)\"",
      "question": "Did the wording of this card change?"
    },
    "cardHistories": [
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/2b165d6a63e53fca7e29",
        "id": "180",
        "fromDate": "2025-08-11T10:25:23+00:00",
        "type": "BALANCING_ERRATUM",
        "name": "Balancing Erratum of Afanas",
        "description": "https://www.altered.gg/news/whispers-from-the-maze-mid-season-patch",
        "answer": "Yes. The first printing of this card said:  \"When you play a Spell — Target Character you control gains 1 boost. (Do this after the spell resolves.)\"  Future versions will say:  \"Spells you play with Hand Cost {1} or less have [Fleeting].  When you play a Spell — Target Character you control gains 1 boost. (Do this after the spell resolves.)\"",
        "question": "Did the wording of this card change?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/6dc526c2ff8fc41d52e1",
        "id": "179",
        "fromDate": "2024-09-06T10:25:23+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Control and 2vs2",
        "description": "https://www.altered.gg/fr-fr/news/the-formats-of-altered-multiplayer",
        "answer": "No. You only control Characters in your Expeditions.",
        "question": "In 2vs2, can I boost a Character controlled by my ally with Afanas & Senka?"
      },
      {
        "@type": "CardHistory",
        "@id": "/.well-known/genid/8e6cd2451cc74dd9ddaf",
        "id": "178",
        "fromDate": "2024-02-05T10:25:23+00:00",
        "type": "RULING",
        "name": "Control and Reserve",
        "answer": "No. Cards in Reserve are not controlled.",
        "question": "Can I boost a Character in my Reserve with Afanas & Senka?"
      }
    ]
  }
}